<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://faversham.pub/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://faversham.pub/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-09-09T18:50:34+00:00</updated><id>https://faversham.pub/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Faversham Pub Reviews</title><subtitle>Discover Faversham’s finest pubs with detailed reviews and traditional insights. Your definitive guide to exploring the best Faversham pubs.</subtitle><author><name>Rhys Adams</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Old Wine Vaults</title><link href="https://faversham.pub/blog/old-wine-vaults" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Old Wine Vaults" /><published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://faversham.pub/blog/old-wine-vaults</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://faversham.pub/blog/old-wine-vaults"><![CDATA[<p>Ah the Old Wine Vaults, one of the most… interesting pubs in Faversham. In the daytime it is almost empty, while at nights it is a very rowdy place indeed.</p>

<p>We arrived at the Wine Vaults around midday, sitting outside. We believed we were only the second group of clients there - but that soon changed after we realised that the other people there were either friends of the landlord or contractors on a break. After 15 minutes or so at our table we noticed the landlord had come to speak to the others about something, before all of them headed up a ladder into the loft area of the pub and stayed there for the remaining 30 minutes of our stay. This was a very peculiar sight.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wine_vaults_2.webp" alt="A trip up the ladded" /></p>

<p>The garden area of the Wine Vaults where we were seated definitely had character. The tables are covered in avian excrement, and the ground littered with old plastic bottles, rubbish and worse.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wine_vaults_1.webp" alt="The state of the tables" /></p>

<p>At one point we were greeted by a rat running past us upon the wall, but he didn’t stop for a chat, probably aware that anyone who frequents the Wine Vaults would probably bite its head off without a second thought.</p>

<p>Like any good pub, the Wine Vaults does not serve food, only liquid refreshments. Talking of liquids, one of the only positives for the pub is the price of a pint. It cost just under 2 pounds for a Strongbow - which in this day and age is almost unheard of, even in Wetherspoons.</p>

<p>Later that day, we returned for an evening of karaoke - a night where one can see who people really are. The good people of Faversham seemed to be having a good evening in the pub, obviously too drunk to care about the shortcomings of the pub. The music choice was acceptable but I would rate the karaoke singers a 4/10 as they were all quite out of tune. The pints were still the same price as before, and there was no cost to take up the microphone.</p>

<p>Overall, I’d rate this pub a 5/10, as compared to other Faverpubs it lacks character, feels slightly unwelcoming with its borderline feral clientele, and is quite dirty inside and out. But the pints being so cheap means that this is most likely not the last time we visit the Old Wine Vaults.</p>

<!--more-->

<h3 id="location-and-interior">Location and Interior</h3>

<p>Central and alluring, the Old Wine Vaults beckons the Faverman away from his family, and into a pit of discombobulation. But what sort of patrons does this attract, are they the Faverfinest? It’s certainly a pub for the people, the vox populi of the council estates. Having the unique ability to make the local Wetherspoons seem gentrified, the Vaults certainly has a character. Like a fish in a pond, the pub disrupts the calmy stagnant water that is Faversham, out of place, unpredictable, and violent. If one is bold enough to enter, they reach a long corridor leading to the bar, with small rooms on the sides filled with usually empty chairs. These areas have been long abandoned, for all congregate in the main room leaving it as buzzing as Selling late into the evening. The room is filled with an evil device, a great disruptor of the true pub, the television. Perhaps this is why the mental growth of its patrons have been so clearly stunted, the volume of the device silences any comprehensible thought, yet alone conversation. On its merits, the décor is of the old sense, I appreciate the exposed woodwork and felt like the homosexual in boytown. On a dichotomic sense, this is strangely the only Faverpub I have visited that has a dress code. Albeit not strict, it makes one wonder the reasons behind its implementation, probably something racial.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wine_vaults_jack_1.webp" alt="The dress code is seldom enforced" /></p>

<h3 id="drinks">Drinks</h3>

<p>At last, I may discuss the great joy of this establishment, the prices. This pub is perfect for the benefits enjoyer, or my friend and I. Cheaper than a Wetherspoons, the Vaults has mastered the practise of diluting a keg, and lovingly pass this discount unto the patron. One can enter with a ‘pony’ and leave with 10 pints of the good stuff. I must discuss the behaviour of the staff, for this has been an experience more diverse than a trip on the Picadilly Line. We are usually grunted at by a ‘woman’ fresh from the streets, desperate for us to pay and depart so she can enjoy another ciggy. On different occasions we have jolly locals, ready to engage in spirited banter with myself over certain glassware looking homosexual. However, on a special occasion, we were greeted by a kind Chap I will name Percy. Percy was proper, he wore a pinstriped waistcoat and served us with manners. I miss Percy and hope to see him soon, hopefully he hasn’t been injured by Sandwich youths. Drink dependent on the server.</p>

<h3 id="food">Food</h3>

<p>Now onto the profundity. The Vaults does not dabble in the culinary business in the standard way, for the product consumed here does not go in through the mouth, but through the nose. What could perhaps have been an old vault of wine, now is likely to hold vast amounts of Cocaine, something that is commonly viewed as illegal. Evidence of this has been seen in the beer garden, as well as in the patron’s souls. It should be renamed Modern Cocaine Vaults for accuracy, though this could make marketing difficult. I have been told the prices in Kent are some of the best in the country, so perhaps stop here for a reasonably priced pick-me-up before continuing your Faveradventure.</p>

<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>

<p>Much here to conclude on. This is a thoroughly dodgy pub which I would not revisit if it were not for the prices. Perhaps in this epoch, if we are to oppose the expansion of the soulless Wetherspoons, this is the alternative. I would advise going for the experience, as one would to the zoo, and staying for a short pint. Perhaps you can drink enough with your money that the surroundings don’t matter, or even better, you ride them by singing karaoke. This is a 4/10, a sad look into what may be the alternative of the Wetherspoons opposition, and a consequence of Western Decline. Please see depictions of the patrons.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wine_vaults_jack_2.webp" alt="A pub patron (artist's impression)" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wine_vaults_jack_3.webp" alt="A pub patron (artist's impression)" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Rhys</name></author><category term="pub" /><category term="faversham" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The old wine vaults is a Craft Union pub located on Preston Street in Faversham. It certainly has character...]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Limes</title><link href="https://faversham.pub/blog/limes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Limes" /><published>2025-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://faversham.pub/blog/limes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://faversham.pub/blog/limes"><![CDATA[<p>The Limes is one of the most frequented pubs for us in Faversham, the standard
and the default. Whenever we go to Faversham, we always start at the Limes.
It seems fitting then that one of the first reviews on this site is about it.</p>

<h3 id="the-pub">The Pub</h3>

<p>The Limes is situated just past the railway station at Faversham, as you make
your way down the high street. The exterior is friendly enough, and walking
through the front door one is greeted by a clean and open bar area.</p>

<p>Upon purchasing a drink, you can either sit at some small 2-person tables
beside the bar, or walk back behind the bar to some very comfy armchairs next
to a fireplace. We very rarely see the fire alight unfortunately - this would
greatly improve the experience.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/limes_6.small.webp" alt="An Unlit Fire" /></p>

<p>Further back from the armchairs are a large circular table - great for groups of
friends having a pub crawl, as should be done when visiting Faversham. Past this
lies a fairly average beer garden.</p>

<p>The interior is fairly nice, however there are very few interesting wares
on the walls - they are rather plain but overall nice enough.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/limes_5.small.webp" alt="Comfy Chairs" /></p>

<h3 id="food-and-drink">Food and Drink</h3>

<p>Standard for a Neame pub, there was Orchard View on tap for the cider option.
It’s an OK cider, but a bit too carbonated and slightly too acidic for my tastes.
Jack had a Guinness as usual, and that requires no comment.</p>

<p>We haven’t ever seen food being served, but we’ve been assured that they do in
fact serve food. This of course means I cannot comment on their food selection.</p>

<h3 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h3>

<p>Overall The Limes is another standard Neame pub - although the interior is nice
enough and the drinks are OK, there is nothing massively special about the pub.</p>

<p>I’m giving it a 7/10 as I have very few faults with it, but I simply feel it
could be so much more if it had something unique to boast.</p>

<!--more-->

<h3 id="location-and-interior">Location and Interior</h3>

<p>The Limes, a very odd name. Where are the Limes? Certainly not in the UK, at least not naturally. One would be mistaken for thinking the name forbodes inside a tropical nightmare, or perhaps, cynically, something bought here from foreign soil. However, this allegory is thankfully in jest, fear not, the soul is pleasantly warmed to find inside a wholesome classic Anglo pub. The bar, like many things, is open and wide, allowing staff to easily socialise with patrons and indulge deeper in the talk of the town. Seating is above average, leather armchairs ‘hide’ to the rear of the bar providing supreme comfort for the working Faverman, these cows did not die in vain. Along to the side there are multiple booths and a larger dining room, whilst terribly modern, this tumour has luckily not yet metastasised, and the majority remains pure. The location is very close to the train station, and on many occasions, one has had a quick pint before dashing for the train, although this I would advise against. Whilst the interior does lack anything unique, it is unapologetically classically average and worth some time. Nobody would feel particularly disappointed or invigorated by coming here, it’s a safe pair of hands.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/limes_3.small.webp" alt="The Exterior" /></p>

<h3 id="drinks">Drinks</h3>

<p>Available is the usual selection for a Neame pub. Whilst very average and unremarkable, the brewery does produce good beers such as the Double Stout. Unfortunately declining in popularity due to the liberalisation of the tastebuds, the drink fortunately remains stalwart here. Although practisers of Neameology must pay heed. On occasion the barman has been known to only accept a voucher for Neame drinks, which excludes Guinness. This is a shadow of the darkest hue and will always remain in my mind, like those who tried to steal from me in Mayfair last November. I did not try the cider as I personally do not dabble with the deviants.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/limes_2.small.webp" alt="The Bar" /></p>

<h3 id="food">Food</h3>

<p>Whilst I did not consume here, the menu seemed Faveraverage in terms of selection and price. I have little to comment on this.</p>

<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>

<p>The Limes makes me think of the restaurant chain Côte, somewhere consistently average where money is well spent. Whilst lacking the perennial spirit, one must consider the joys of the normative. It is certainly true there are rooms for improvement in making this truly a landmark, but one contemplates that this normality isn’t actually that bad. In pursuing the exceptional, there is always the risk of falling below the normal. There is merit in a contented baseline and this is important. I would advise patrons to stop for two pints if they are using the station. This would set you up well for travels towards the hub of commerce known as Selling. Keep in mind the Lime, quite oxymoronic in its name, an exotic fruit but a very classically average pub. This is like a trip to Norwich. I rate this a 6.5. This sets a good mark for a traditional pub and harks a hymn to the silent majority whilst setting the ground for the mediocrity versus excellence showdown of pubs to come.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rhys</name></author><category term="pub" /><category term="faversham" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Limes is an interesting Shepherd Neame pub located on the bustling Faversham highstreet. We review the drinks and atmosphere.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Albion Taverna</title><link href="https://faversham.pub/blog/albion-taverna" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Albion Taverna" /><published>2024-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://faversham.pub/blog/albion-taverna</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://faversham.pub/blog/albion-taverna"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-pub">The Pub</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/albion_taverna_2b.small.webp" alt="Outside View" /></p>

<p>The Albion Taverna is a pub which has a promising name - literally meaning
the tavern of Britain. It is one of the further pubs from Faversham high street,
but not too much of a trek.</p>

<p>We visited around 2:30pm, and since it’s winter the sun was already starting to
set. We still decided to sit down outside in order to see the Standard Quay, even
though at this time of year it looks a bit of a mess…</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/albion_taverna_1.small.webp" alt="The View" /></p>

<p>The atmosphere in the pub is more restaurant-like than pub-like, which isn’t to
say it’s bad, however it’s not quite the experience one hopes for when going
to a pub.</p>

<h3 id="drinks">Drinks</h3>

<p>I had a Kentish Pip craftsman cider - it was decent, but did cost me almost £6,
a bit steep for today.</p>

<p>My friend had a Christmas Ale - he said it was very good, although had far too
much sediment, as you can see below. His pint set him back a more standard £5.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/albion_taverna_3.small.webp" alt="Sediment" /></p>

<h3 id="food">Food</h3>

<p>We didn’t try the food in the Taverna, since the cheapest main available was £17.
This put us off ordering, although it did smell delicious! They serve mainly
Mexican food and have quite good reviews from others.</p>

<hr />

<p>Overall, the Albion Taverna is a fairly standard Shepherd Neame pub - slightly
expensive drinks, not a massive amount of character, but with some brilliant
drinks available, mostly brewed locally. The worst part however of the visit:
when returning our glasses and thanking the barman, I was ignored!</p>

<!--more-->

<h3 id="location-and-interior">Location and Interior</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/albion_taverna_4.small.webp" alt="View of the pub exterior" /></p>

<p>The Albion Taverna, a strong name that secretes patriotic fervor. Will it do
its name justice? Or like a political party, be little more than a soulless
machination of ineffectual grandstanding? First, we must consider location.
Situated on the banks of the River Fav, patrons are greeted with the sight of
the Shepherd Neame brewery. As the air lingers with a hoppy tinge, one is left
to contemplate how the company has affected Faversham, to what extent does a
business go from being local to corporate; has Neame lost its roots? A question
for another post perhaps. Alas the view is undoubtedly extraordinary, no other
Faverpub rivals this. Although the reader must pay heed, the interior is
ghastly. Lacking anything unique, the décor is substandard and unimaginative.
All it would take is a short walk to the local antique shop and £200, this is
not a job for Liberty or Harrods. I would recommend they expand their forward
exterior seating; the majority is behind the pub giving drinkers a lovely view
of the car park, useful for a town such as Sandwich or Headcorn, respectively
filled with groups of tenebrous youths or ridden with criminals eyeing any
catalytic converters, but luckily not for Faversham. Yet. I have mixed feelings
on the exterior architecture, it reminds me of a car park in Whitstable. I
don’t like that car park but for some it may feel appropriate for the Standard
Quay. I would perhaps change the colour to avoid it being mistaken for
corrugated iron, reminiscent of the Third World. The seats are uncomfortable
and childlike. This must change.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/albion_taverna_5.small.webp" alt="Outside view of the river Fav" /></p>

<h3 id="drinks-1">Drinks</h3>

<p>It has to be said the drink selection is rather impressive for a Neame pub, I
was delighted by the cocktail offerings, an unusual sight in Faversham. The
cocktails were well made, the staff were knowledgeable, but I dare not ask for
something not on the small menu, that would be dangerous. I rather enjoyed the
Christmas Ale, the weak would claim it to be seasonal but a good drink can be
had whenever. I think the sort of people that say “seasonal” are pretentious.
But, was this too good to be true? Indeed, it was, I was saddened to find an
exceptional amount of Sediment lurking in the depths of my glass, ready to
position itself within my arteries and create a blockage. My thoughts were
surprisingly of unmelancholy, for I found solace in yet again proving the
existence of the Sediment to my ever-denying friend. I can only hope he lives a
longer life as a result, and if the cost of that is 50ml of ale, then so be it.
I will not comment on the ciders as I am personally not interested
in the private activities associated with it’s drinkers. Prices were Faveraverage.</p>

<h3 id="food-1">Food</h3>

<p>Being on a budget, I did not choose to consume at this pub as it was rather
expensive. This sentiment was only furthered by the choice of cuisine –
Mexican. I realised it as soon as I walked in, the odour of Cajun craziness
assaulted my nostrils. I regretted trimming my nose hair like those who remove
sandbags before a storm, and instantly felt queasy. This was deeply wrong. A
pub bearing Brittania serving Mexican food? I felt like I were in a hip hop
video. Mexicans have substantially lower productivity than most, I suspect
sales of dishes at this “Taverna” can be correlated with the productivity of
Faversham. Overall, the food was overpriced and immoral. Do not eat here.</p>

<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>

<p>Ah the Albion Taverna, microcosmic of our society. A pub in a good location and
access to many drinks, yet lacking the defining perennial. The owners thinking
they were unique in having ethnic cuisine only add arsenic to the mind. I rate
this pub a solid 5.5, it is not her fault but that of the owners. It has great
potential, unlike the West, this pub can be saved. All that is needed is a
return to traditional Anglo food and an eclectic interior to match the stunning
scenery with an overall focus on its “quay” strength, the location. Do visit
and have an ale outside, stay for an hour, and observe the Fav and the Brewery.
But make no mistake, this is not Albion, this is a direct mockery to history. A
more apt name would be the Lonely Sombrero, harking to Mexico, but also an
honest isolationism to the Mexicans in our country. This could be a 9 if the
issues are resolved, but we must ask, do the owners have the will to divert
from their Mexican course?</p>]]></content><author><name>Rhys</name></author><category term="pub" /><category term="faversham" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Albion Taverna is an interesting Shepherd Neame pub located on the Standard Quay in Faversham. Read for insights into drinks, views and controversy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to faversham.pub</title><link href="https://faversham.pub/blog/welcome-to-faversham-pub" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to faversham.pub" /><published>2024-11-24T14:13:23+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-24T14:13:23+00:00</updated><id>https://faversham.pub/blog/welcome-to-faversham-pub</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://faversham.pub/blog/welcome-to-faversham-pub"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to faversham.pub! This website will eventually contain reviews of every
pub in Faversham, and possibly including pubs from elsewhere.</p>

<p>At faversham.pub, we love Faversham and everything in it - it is the essence of
Kent and Great Britain - and hope that by reading this blog, you’ll love it too.</p>]]></content><author><name>Rhys Adams</name></author><category term="meta" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to our blog! Join us as we explore Faversham’s historic pubs, review the best spots for a pint, and celebrate the rich legacy of Shepherd Neame brewery.]]></summary></entry></feed>